<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wissen Xue Blog</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/</link><description>Recent content on Wissen Xue Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 08:22:04 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://h.acethon.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Troubleshooting Oracle Cloud Compute Instance Serial Console Access via Local SSH</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/oracle-cloud-computer-instance-serial-console/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 08:22:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/oracle-cloud-computer-instance-serial-console/</guid><description>This post walks through resolving a common issue when connecting to the Oracle Cloud Compute Instance serial console using SSH on macOS or Linux.
1. Review the Oracle Documentation Start by reading the official guide on connecting to the serial console. This article specifically focuses on the section: Using an SSH client on macOS or Linux.
2. Create a Serial Console Connection In the Oracle Cloud Console:
Navigate to Compute &amp;gt; Instances.</description></item><item><title>Setup Xubuntu Desktop in a Macbook Pro</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/setup-xubuntu-in-mpb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:20:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/setup-xubuntu-in-mpb/</guid><description>Burn a bootable USB dongle and boot the macbook pro with it Try and install Follow this link with mac book pro HW to setup Xubuntu. Pay attention to the describe on how to using private wifi driver:
If you're WIFI is not working, then open the start menu, search &amp;quot;driver&amp;quot; and click on &amp;quot;Additional Drivers&amp;quot; and that should find what you need. Otherwise, you may need to resolving the missing driver issue using ethernet after installing.</description></item><item><title>Using a Private GitHub Repository to Deploy a Hugo Blog on Cloudflare CDN</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/private-hugo-ws-and-publish-to-cf-cdn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 23:00:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/private-hugo-ws-and-publish-to-cf-cdn/</guid><description>This is a step-by-step guide on how to use Hugo to create a blog site, manage your content and configuration in a private GitHub repository, and deploy it to Cloudflare Pages, which offers global CDN acceleration and built-in web security.
1. Create a New Hugo Site Follow the official Hugo Quick Start Guide to set up your new site. Make sure to initialize Git and add your theme as a submodule.</description></item><item><title>Publish Hugo site with Github Actions</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/publish-hugo-site-with-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 16:11:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/publish-hugo-site-with-github-actions/</guid><description>Thanks aneesahammed&amp;rsquo;s blog, I finally made it. Now my hugo site (this blog) has used the Github Actions to publish to Github Pages.
My Hugo site workspace is in a private github repository and my pulished site is in a public repository. Most of the article about publishing Hugo site and Github pages are talking about the same github repository with diffrent branch. Then finally I found aneesahammed&amp;rsquo;s blog and this is exactly what I need.</description></item><item><title>How Check the Password of the Transmission in Docker</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/check-the-password-of-the-transmission-in-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 20:13:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/check-the-password-of-the-transmission-in-docker/</guid><description>how to start a Transmission in Docker docker run --name transmissionbt --restart=always -d -e TZ=Hongkong -e USERID=1001 -e GROUPID=1001 -v /your/local/path/to/transmission:/var/lib/transmission-daemon -p 9091:9091 -p 51413:51413 dperson/transmission how to check the password: first get the console of the container:
docker exec -it transmissionbt /bin/sh
then in the shell console of the container:
ps -ef | grep transmission you will seee the password transmis 0:11 transmission-daemon --allowed * --blocklist --config-dir /var/lib/transmission-daemon/info --foreground --log-info --no-portmap --auth --username admin --password aaabbbccc</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Time Machine</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/raspberry-pi-time-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 16:10:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/raspberry-pi-time-machine/</guid><description>https://gregology.net/2018/09/raspberry-pi-time-machine/ This one is useful for the USB disk in fstab and delay mount in crontab
https://github.com/odarriba/docker-timemachine I always use Docker as possible as I can to simplify the deployment</description></item><item><title>Mac OS X Backup in Single Mode</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/mac-os-x-recovery-in-single-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 13:21:02 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/mac-os-x-recovery-in-single-mode/</guid><description>Backup files in Mac OS X single mode https://thinkinginsoftware.blogspot.com/2014/03/mac-osx-not-booting-make-backup-from.html https://alvinalexander.com/mac-os-x/mac-osx-single-user-mode-usb-drive https://jesperh.se/osx-backup-from-single-user-mode/ https://gist.github.com/kwcto/45e0b985071fad655e17 Migrating Outlook 2016 from one Mac to a new one https://answers.microsoft.com/en-us/msoffice/forum/all/migrating-outlook-2016-from-one-mac-to-a-new-one/e21b2fc2-b601-4abe-bcdc-bdedad876075</description></item><item><title>A quick notes on how to use Hugo to do personal publication</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/quick-notes-on-hugo-publication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 17:49:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/quick-notes-on-hugo-publication/</guid><description>Hugo related Hugo Home Hugo directory structures Hugo Themes related https://themes.gohugo.io/hyde-hyde/ https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-theme-m10c/ https://themes.gohugo.io/monopriv/ https://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-theme-introduction/ https://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-fresh/ hyde-hyde options https://petercheng.net/posts/website-v2-setup/ https://github.com/htr3n/hyde-hyde/blob/master/exampleSite/config.toml static sites hosting: surge.sh netlify static sites hosting reference: https://superdevresources.com/host-static-website-free/ https://www.slant.co/topics/2256/~best-static-website-hosting-provider Work with git submodule git submodule tutorials TODO customize the blog. (layout/color/Portfolio) publish to gitlab. study how to publish to surge.sh and netlify study Front Matter</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 23:02:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/about/</guid><description>I’m a senior solutions architecture working in CDN&amp;amp;Edge Computing Area. I like Docker/Python/Git. This blog will be used as my technical notes mainly.</description></item><item><title>The first post in this blog</title><link>https://h.acethon.com/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 21:46:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://h.acethon.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>This is my new blog hosting on github pages with Hugo, I will write my notes mostly in technical area and sometimes in other area such as thoughts, stories, ideas and life
Hope this may help myself and others.</description></item></channel></rss>